# **Thomas Seropian**

French & Lebanese dual nationalities
Currently based in London, United Kingdom

Phone: +44 74 2362 9937 E-mail: thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

# **Technology Manager / Chief Technologist**

### Skillset

Software development. Team recruitment and management. Agile delivery.

Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation.

Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Group training and capacity building.

Creativity and flexibility. Project management. Architecture, design and development of web applications.

Technology management in development environment, innovation, ICT4D, entrepreneurship, media.

Establishment and management of a team of 4 technologists in London for an international NGO.

## Work experience

**Technology manager** for an international NGO **Internews** London, United Kingdom – 2015 – present (www.internews.org)

→ Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects

Overseeing recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists. Ensuring planning, coordination and distribution of work, setting priorities, agreeing detailed work plans, budgets and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members, performance management following agile methodologies. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap with a strong focus on scalability, quality & security.

→ Leading the design, development and delivery of innovation and technology activities

Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local media ecosystems among the most repressive regimes.

Managing and monitoring activities' budgets. Designing rapid response to urgent needs for support from partners in the field.

→ Strategic Development and Learning

Leading the design and implementation of policies and guidelines for technologies activities. Evangelize agile methodology and practice. Conceptualizing and design of innovative approaches for using technology in closed countries. Participating to fund-raising. Representing at conferences and events.

Proposal planning. Improving quality of development processes (including specification, operations, testing, deployment, policy writing...);

Freelance consultant in open source technologies
Self Employed London, United Kingdom 2014-2015 (www.seropian.io)

- ightarrow Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- $\rightarrow$  Areas of work: E-Commerce, ERP web applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription-based application, including automated online payments for a start-ups incubator. Iterative Prototyping of CRM and back office applications

Developed web based Intranet including import/export modules for a travel booking agent.

Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

Implemented a Git driven process for development and deployment for the application.

→ Training and mentoring on digital security, online privacy and cryptography

Trained Digital Security and online privacy to journalists and European institutions members.

# ICT Projects manager / Web application engineer for an international NGO Internews Europe Paris, France / London, United Kingdom 2009-2013 (www.internews.eu)

→ On-line freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications

Writing user stories & specifications during inception. Managing external contractors and developer.

Developing and maintaining custom modules. Integration with third party providers APIs.

Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support with teams.

Managing technical resources & back-office infrastructures.

Managing back-offices for ICT activities: web platforms, secure hosting & video platforms. Deploying and monitoring cloud based infrastructure.

Building, delivering and facilitating trainings & trainers on ICT topics

Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA, Europe)

# **Software engineer** for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France 2008 (www.hellotipi.com)

ightarrow Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped registration process. Multilingual support & more.

Managed client support, designed tutorials, wrote blog posts.

#### ICT projects manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia 2006-2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer trainings in youth training centres. Developed activities in 2 major cities. Managed recruitment of local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated to feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

**Assistant manager** for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France 2005 (www.valeo.com)

Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

# **Technology stack**

OO PHP (MVC), Drupal, Javascript (jQuery, Node.js), HTML5, Bootstrap, SASS, RESTful APIs, AWS (EC2, S3, Cloudfront, Route53, IAM), MySQL, Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), Ansible, Docker, Apache, Nginx, Solr, GIT, SVN, JSON, XML, Selenium

#### Education

#### **MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation**

#### Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 $\rightarrow$  Graduated with first class honours.

# **Foreign languages**

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner